Guide to the John Dirk Walecka Notebooks and Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John Dirk Walecka notebooks and papers
1960-1986
SC0424
Walecka, John Dirk, 1932-
3.25 Linear feet
Notes, lectures and reports on nuclear theory, general relativity, quantum mechanics, and mathematical physics. Collection also includes reprints and some correspondence.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of John D. Walecka, 1990.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Walecka, a.b. Harvard 1954 and Ph.D. MIT 1958, joined the Stanford faculty in 1960; he was chair of the Physics Department from 1977 to 1982. He left Stanford in 1987 to be the scientific director of the Continuous Electron Beam Accelerator Facility (CEBAF) in Newport News, VA.
Description of the Collection
Notes, lectures and reports on nuclear theory, general relativity, quantum mechanics, and mathematical physics. Collection also includes reprints and some correspondence.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Department of Physics. Faculty.; Stanford University. Department of Physics.; Walecka, John Dirk, 1932-; Nuclear physics --Study and teaching.; Quantum theory --Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - 241-243: Nuclear Theory, 1960-61 (Box 1)
  - 338: General Relativity, undated (Box 1)
  - Lectures on Dispersion Theory, undated (Box 1)
  - 330-332: Advanced Quantum Mechanics, 1962-63 (Box 1)
  - 340: M. B. Theory, 1964-65 (Box 1)
  - 341: Nuclear Theory, 1964-65 (Box 2)
  - 342: Nuclear Theory, 1964-65 (Box 2)
  - 340: M. B. Theory, 1965-66 (Box 2)
  - 341: Nuclear Theory, 1965-66 (Box 2)
  - 342: Nuclear Theory, 1965-66 (Box 2)
  - 330: Advanced Quantum Mechanics, 1966-67 (Box 2)
  - 331: Advanced Quantum Mechanics, 1966-67 (Box 2)
  - 332: Advanced Quantum Mechanics, 1966-67 (Box 3)
  - 330: Advanced Quantum Mechanics, 1967-68 (Box 3)
  - 331: Advanced Quantum Mechanics, 1967-68 (Box 3)
  - 332: Advanced Quantum Mechanics, 1967-68 (Box 3)
  - 270: Statistical Mechanics, 1967-68 (Box 3)
  - 210: Advanced Mechanics, 1970-71 (Box 3)
  - 211: Mathematical Physics, 1970-71 (Box 3)
  - 370: Theory Condensed Matter, 1970-71 (Box 3)
  - 210: Advanced Mechanics, 1971-72 (Box 4)
  - 211: Mathematical Physics, 1971-72 (Box 4)
  - 210: Advanced Quantum Mechanics, 1972-73 (Box 4)
  - 331: Advanced Quantum Mechanics, 1973-74 (Box 4)
  - 332: Advanced Quantum Mechanics, 1973-74 (Box 4)
  - 230: Quantum Mechanics, 1974-75 (Box 4)
  - 231: Quantum Mechanics, 1974-75 (Box 4)
  - 232: Quantum Mechanics, 1974-75 (Box 5)
  - 230: Quantum Mechanics, 1975-76 (Box 5)
  - 231: Quantum Mechanics, 1975-76 (Box 5)
  - 232: Quantum Mechanics, 1975-76 (Box 5)
  - Various Physics reprints, notes and correspondence 1 (Box 6)
  - Various Physics reprints, notes and correspondence 2 (Box 6)
  - Various Physics reprints, notes and correspondence 3 (Box 6)
  - Various Physics reprints, notes and correspondence 4 (Box 6)
  - Various Physics reprints, notes and correspondence 5 (Box 6)
  - Report of Task Force #1 Ad Hoc Panel on the Future of Nuclear Science. Subnuclear aspects of the nucleons in the nucleus. Fourth draft, April 4, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Electron Scattering and Nuclear Structure. Talk for the L. I. Schiff Memorial Session A. P. A. Meeting, San Francisco, California, Feb. 3, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Memo from Walecka: Report of the Subpanel on the State of Development of Nuclear Physics. undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - NSF proposal (renewal) for “Studies in Theoretical Physics” 1983 (Box 7, Folder 4)